Guide to the Robert K. Merton Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Reference and Research, 1933-2002
  - Subject Files and Topical Interests
    - Self-Fulfilling Prophecy
      - Simmel, Georg, Anticipation of, 1996 (Box 480, Folder 9)
      - and Unanticipated Consequences, 1973-1974, 1986-1996 (Box 480, Folder 10)
      - Usages in Norway, 1965-1966, 1981-1991 (Box 480, Folder 11)
    - Self-Fulfilling Retrospect, 1996 (Box 480, Folder 12)
    - Social Structure and Anomie
      - General, 1983-1992, (3 Folders) (Box 480, Folder 13 to 15)
      - Anthologized, 1985 (Box 481, Folder 1)
      - Articles, 1983-1995, (5 Folders) (Box 481, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Bennett, James, 1984-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 481, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Bibliographies, undated (Box 482, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1982-1989 (Box 482, Folder 2)
        - Cullen, Francis and Messner, Steven, 1986-1989 (Box 482, Folder 3)
      - Current Contents Essay, 1987 (Box 482, Folder 4)
      - Diffusion, 1983-1985 (Box 482, Folder 5)
      - Discussion Peripheral to Opportunity Structure, 1978-1985 (Box 482, Folder 6)
      - Last Minute Changes to Terminology, 1938 (Box 482, Folder 7)
      - Original Course Lecture Notes and Draft for Paper, 1937 (Box 482, Folder 8)
    - Socially Expected Durations
      - General, 1973-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 482, Folder 9 to 10)
      - General, 1973-1994, (6 Folders) (Box 483, Folder 1 to 6)
      - General, 1973-1994, (5 Folders) (Box 484, Folder 1 to 5)
      - General, 1973-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 485, Folder 1 to 2)
      - American Sociological Review--Correspondence--Stryker, Sheldon, 1983-1983 (Box 485, Folder 3)
      - Audio Recordings, 1983 (2 Audio Cassette Tapes) (Box 507)
      - Burt, Ronald, 1977-1998 (Box 485, Folder 4)
      - Case of "Sojourners," 1975-1985 (Box 485, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 485, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Deadlines
        - General, 1977-1983 (Box 485, Folder 8)
        - Case of Citizen Marx, 1978 (Box 485, Folder 9)
      - Expected Occupancy of Status, 1975-1980, (2 Folders) (Box 485, Folder 10 to 11)
      - Friendship, undated (Box 486, Folder 1)
      - Idiom and the Vernacular, 1978-1982 (Box 486, Folder 2)
      - Illness--Chronic and Terminal, undated (Box 486, Folder 3)
      - In the Law, 1973-1983 (Box 486, Folder 4)
      - In Sports, 1974-1984 (Box 486, Folder 5)
      - Lame Duck, 1978-1982 (Box 486, Folder 6)
      - Lecture for American Sociological Association--Drafts, 1982 (Box 486, Folder 7)
      - Lectures and Publications on, 1977-1982 (Box 486, Folder 8)
      - Length as Parameter, 1972-1977 (Box 486, Folder 9)
      - Lincoln-Douglas Debates, 1986 (Box 486, Folder 10)
      - Longevity and Death, 1978-1983 (Box 486, Folder 11)
      - Nixon, Kennedy, Carter, Ford, 1962 (Box 486, Folder 12)
      - Notre Dame Notes, 1971-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 486, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Old Lectures on Age as a Concept, 1958-1975 (Box 486, Folder 15)
      - Original Manuscript Prior to Cuts for Publication, 1983 (Box 487, Folder 1)
      - Parameters of, 1978-1982 (Box 487, Folder 2)
      - Precocity, Prodigy, and the Roger Cotes Syndrome, 1977 (Box 487, Folder 3)
      - Professional-Client Relationship, 1977 (Box 487, Folder 4)
      - Reading Copy, 1984-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 487, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Retirement, 1977-1978 (Box 487, Folder 7)
      - Role-Set Materials, undated (Box 487, Folder 8)
      - Salience of Durations, undated (Box 487, Folder 9)
      - Social Space-Social Time, 1982-1983 (Box 487, Folder 10)
      - Speed Parameter, undated (Box 487, Folder 11)
      - Statute of Limitations, 1979-1982 (Box 487, Folder 12)
      - Succession and Residence, undated (Box 487, Folder 13)
      - Tabboni, Simonetta, 1987 (Box 487, Folder 14)
      - Tenure, 1978-1983 (Box 487, Folder 15)
      - Theory Items, 1964-1970, 1982-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 487, Folder 16 to 17)
      - Universality, Mortality, and Death Sentence from Birth, 1984-1986 (Box 488, Folder 1)
      - Unpublished, 1982 (Box 488, Folder 2)
      - Various Sports, undated (Box 488, Folder 3)
      - War, 1977 (Box 488, Folder 4)
    - Sociological Words, Concepts, Jargon, and Paradigms, 1970-2002, (3 Folders) (Box 488, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Sociology of Knowledge, 1945-1964, undated (Box 488, Folder 8)
    - Status Sets--Smith, Robert B., 1990-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 489, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Thomas Theorem
      - General, 1995 (Box 489, Folder 3)
      - Data Used, 1981-1995 (Box 489, Folder 4)
      - Night Thoughts, 1994-1995 (Box 489, Folder 5)
      - Ogburn, W.F.--Counter Example and Natural Experiment, undated (Box 489, Folder 6)
      - Partially Used Data, 1987-1995 (Box 489, Folder 7)
      - Social Forces, 1993-1995 (Box 489, Folder 8)
      - Thomas, William Isaac, 1984-1995 (Box 489, Folder 9)
    - Unanticipated Consequences
      - General, 1974-1999, (5 Folders) (Box 490, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Articles
        - General, 1952-1962, 1995-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 490, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Boudon, Raymond, 1979-1980, (2 Folders) (Box 491, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Marx, Gary T., 1980 (Box 491, Folder 3)
        - Sieber, Sam D., 1978 (Box 491, Folder 4)
      - Book--Table of Contents and Drafts, 1977-1980 (Box 491, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 491, Folder 6)
      - Important Collaterals, undated (Box 491, Folder 7)
      - "Invisible Hand," 1982-1990 (Box 491, Folder 8)
      - Jokisch, Rodrigo, 1982 (Box 491, Folder 9)
      - Key Offprints, 1962-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 492, Folder 1 to 2)
      - and Kindred Ideas: A Sociological Perspective--Draft, undated (Box 492, Folder 3)
      - and Kindred Sociological Ideas
        - Amalfi Conference, 1986-1989 (Box 492, Folder 4)
        - Draft, undated (Box 492, Folder 5)
      - Lecture Notes, 1943-1975, (2 Folders) (Box 492, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Notes and Correspondence, 1954, 1976-1982 (Box 492, Folder 8)
      - Notes on History of Personal Interest in Subject, 1961-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 493, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Of Purposive Social Action
        - General, 1977-1990 (2 Folder) (Box 493, Folder 3 to 4)
        - Lipset, Martin, 1988 (Box 493, Folder 5)
        - The Washington Post, 1992-1995 (Box 493, Folder 6)
      - Of Social Action, 1994 (Box 493, Folder 7)
      - Pool, Robert--Beyond Engineering Feedback, 1996 (Box 493, Folder 8)
      - Relationship Between Unanticipated and Unrecognized Consequences, 1950 (Box 493, Folder 9)
      - Schneider, Louis, 1973-1979 (Box 494, Folder 1)
      - and Self-Fulfilling Prophecy, 1975-1994, (4 Folders) (Box 494, Folder 2 to 5)
      - The Society for the Study of Social Problems Annual Meeting, 1977-1978 (Box 494, Folder 6)
      - Tenner, Edward, 1991 (Box 494, Folder 7)
      - van den Daele, Wolf, 1980-1982 (Box 494, Folder 8)
      - Wippler, Reinhard, 1977-1982 (Box 494, Folder 9)
    - Whewell, William--As Terminologist, 2002 (Box 494, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Studies and Projects, 1935-1997
  This series provides a framework for understanding key sociological studies and projects conducted by Merton in the mid-twentieth century. Project documentation includes analyses of publications, general surveys, and proposed project topics. Study materials, which comprise the bulk of the series, cover Merton's early sociological pursuits, mainly while he was involved with the Bureau of Applied Social Research at Columbia University. Of note are original interviews, questionnaires, and journals of study participants, which provide an unfiltered look at American social thought and attitude regarding social and cultural issues, education, and careers. These are particularly evidenced in the Ethnic Opinionnaires completed in the 1940s. The records also reflect the evolution of Merton's studies into larger bodies of work, such as publications and conferences. This series is particularly important as it illuminates early social research methodology. A good portion of the records include notes, proposals for funding, drafts of questionnaires, and memoranda related to execution of studies. The studies were also used in Merton's courses and seminars at Columbia University as a means of teaching sociology students about research practices.
  Major studies reflected in Series VI include the Housing study, the Manhattanville project, the Expert study, the study of Medical Education and the Eisenhower mail study. The Housing study analyzed a mixed race public housing community and Merton used these findings to examine social concepts, such as friendship, from a sociological perspective. Several publications derived from the study, most notably Patterns of Social Life: Explorations in the Sociology of Housing, are represented in the series. The Manhattanville project was conducted in the early 1950s and records consist of extensive interviews with members of the Manhattanville neighborhood in New York. These interviews were used to determine the community's occupational aspirations and success models. This study relied heavily on participant interviews and observation and detailed transcripts and field reports are contained here. The Expert study focused on several separate case studies to understand the utilization of social sciences and scientists in business and government. The study evolved into several published works, which are represented in the series. The Sociological Study of Medical Education records include interviews and journals from students in medical programs at Cornell, University of Pennsylvania and Western Reserve. Material also includes codebooks, correspondence, and memoranda related to the study. Of note is a folder titled: 'Analysis of Material for Concept Formation.' These are items from the study compiled by Merton many years later and examined for early usage of concepts and phrases, such as role model. Additional material regarding publications from this study are located in Subseries VII.3. The Eisenhower mail study was an attempt by Merton, Joan Goldhamer, and other Bureau of Applied Social Research affiliates to analyze approximately 20,000 letters, postcards and telegrams received by General Dwight D. Eisenhower in 1948 urging him to become candidate for the presidency of the United States. Midway through the project, Eisenhower's team asked the Bureau to abandon the study, giving no explanation. In 1998 Joan Goldhamer published a follow up article entitled "General Eisenhower in academe: A clash of perspectives and a study suppressed." Contained in this series are unpublished documents related to the original mail study, including transcripts of a meeting between Merton and Eisenhower, memoranda, correspondence, and initial drafts. Items pertaining to the revival of the study include correspondence and Goldhamer's drafts containing Merton's edits.
  Series VI is arranged alphabetically by name of study or project
  - Adlai Stevenson Mass Mail Project (aborted), 1953-1954 (Box 196, Folder 5)
  - American Sociological Review Analysis, circa 1965 (Box 352, Folder 1)
  - Bell Telephone Study, 1948-1956 (Box 196, Folder 6)
  - Center for the Social Sciences--American Author Surveys, 1980, (3 Folders) (Box 196, Folder 7-9)
  - Center for the Social Sciences--American Author Surveys, 1980, (6 Folders) (Box 197, Folder 1-6)
  - Center for the Social Sciences--American Author Surveys, 1980, (6 Folders) (Box 198, Folder 1-6)
  - Center for the Social Sciences--American Author Surveys, 1980, (2 Folders) (Box 199, Folder 1-2)
  - Conditions Attendant on the Closing of Intake by Transient Bureaus, 1935 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Dictionary of National Biography Analyses
    - General, 1958, (3 Folders) (Box 352, Folder 2-4)
    - Philosophical Transactions, undated (Box 352, Folder 5)
  - Dictionary of Urban Data Project, 1946 (Box 352, Folder 6)
  - Edward Condon Study--"Trial by Newspaper," 1949 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Eisenhower Mail Study
    - Code, 1948 (Box 199, Folder 5)
    - Conversation with Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1949 (Box 199, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - IBM, 1949 (Box 199, Folder 7)
      - and Memoranda, 1948-1950, (3 Folders) (Box 199, Folder 8-10)
    - Drafts, 1949 (Box 199, Folder 11)
    - Drafts, 1949 (Box 200, Folder 1)
    - Revival of Study
      - Correspondence, 1969, 1981-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 200, Folder 3-4)
      - "General Eisenhower in Academe: A Clash of Perspectives and a Study Suppressed" by Joan Goldhamer
        - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 200, Folder 5)
        - Drafts and Edits, 1985-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 200, Folder 6-7)
      - Notes, 1992 (Box 200, Folder 8)
      - Research Materials, 1982-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 200, Folder 9-10)
    - Summary and Digest, 1949 (Box 200, Folder 2)
  - Ethnic Opinionnaires
    - Completed Surveys, circa 1938, (3 Folders) (Box 201, Folder 1-3)
    - "Facts and Factitiousness in Ethnic Opinionnaires," 1940-1953 (Box 201, Folder 4)
    - Questionnaires and Effect on Research, 1943, (3 Folders) (Box 201, Folder 5-7)
    - Rapport in Use of Opinionnaire, 1943, undated (Box 201, Folder 8)
  - Expert Study
    - General, 1947-1948, (2 Folders) (Box 201, Folder 9-10)
    - AT&T
      - General, 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 201, Folder 11-12)
      - "Applied Social Research and Business decisions: A Preliminary Case Report," 1951 (Box 201, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1956 (Box 201, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1956 (Box 202, Folder 1)
      - Criteria, 1949 (Box 202, Folder 2)
      - Employee Survey, 1948 (Box 202, Folder 3)
      - Interviews with Staff, 1946-1949 (Box 202, Folder 4)
      - Presentation of Research Findings, 1950 (Box 202, Folder 5)
      - Smith, C.T., 1955 (Box 202, Folder 6)
      - Sociology Workshop, 1964-1970, (3 Folders) (Box 202, Folder 7-9)
      - "Some Factors Affecting the Initiation of Applied Social Research," circa 1940s (Box 202, Folder 10)
      - The Role of Social Research in Business Administration: A Case Study Based Primarily Upon the >1930-1949 Experience of the Opinion Research Section of the Chief Statistician's Division of AT&T (with E.C. Devereux, Jr.)--Drafts and Working Papers, circa 1950s, (8 Folders) (Box 203, Folder 1-8)
      - The Role of Social Research in Business Administration: A Case Study Based Primarily Upon the 1930-1949 Experience of the Opinion Research Section of the Chief Statistician's Division of AT&T (with E.C. Devereux, Jr.)--Drafts and Working Papers, circa 1950s (Box 204, Folder 1)
    - Background Research Material, circa 1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 204, Folder 2-3)
    - Budget, 1949-1950 (Box 204, Folder 4)
    - Carnegie Corporation
      - Correspondence and Reports, 1948-1953 (Box 204, Folder 5)
      - Grant, 1948-1949 (Box 204, Folder 6)
    - Conference on the Expert and Applied Social Science, 1948 (Box 204, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - A, 1948-1949 (Box 204, Folder 8)
      - B, 1950 (Box 204, Folder 9)
      - C, 1946-1948 (Box 204, Folder 10)
      - D-F, 1949-1951 (Box 204, Folder 11)
      - Hatt, Paul, 1948-1949 (Box 204, Folder 12)
      - J-M, 1948-1949 (Box 204, Folder 13)
      - P, 1948-1949 (Box 204, Folder 14)
      - R-Z, 1948-1949 (Box 204, Folder 15)
    - "The Expert in Applied Social Science," 1943-1948, (3 Folders) (Box 204, Folder 16-18)
    - "The Expert in Applied Social Science," 1943-1948 (Box 205, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters, 1948-1949 (Box 205, Folder 2)
    - Index of Material, 1948 (Box 205, Folder 3)
    - Interview--Glock, Charles, 1948 (Box 205, Folder 4)
    - Market Research Council, 1949 (Box 205, Folder 5)
    - Meeting Notes, 1948 (Box 205, Folder 6)
    - Memoranda
      - General, 1948-1949, (4 Folders) (Box 205, Folder 7-10)
      - Devereux, E.C., 1949 (Box 205, Folder 11)
      - Hatt, Paul, 1948 (Box 205, Folder 12)
    - Office of War Information
      - Anti-Inflation Study, 1942-1944, (2 Folders) (Box 205, Folder 13-14)
      - Interviews--Tentative Outline, 1948 (Box 205, Folder 15)
      - Summary Memoranda, 1948 (Box 205, Folder 16)
    - Panel of Experts, 1950-1951 (Box 206, Folder 1)
    - Panel of Research Directors, 1951 (Box 206, Folder 2)
    - Public Opinion Polls
      - American Association of Public Opinion Research, 1949 (Box 206, Folder 3)
      - Background Research Material, 1948 (Box 206, Folder 4)
      - Editor Poll, 1948-1949 (Box 206, Folder 7)
      - "Election Polling Forecasts and Public Images of Social Science"--Notes and Drafts, 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 206, Folder 5-6)
      - Memoranda, 1947 (Box 206, Folder 8)
      - Replies from Editors, 1948-1949, (3 Folders) (Box 206, Folder 9-11)
    - Puerto Rican Population, 1948-1949 (Box 207, Folder 1)
    - Requests, 1948-1953 (Box 207, Folder 2)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1947 (Box 207, Folder 3)
    - Transcription, 1949 (Box 207, Folder 4)
    - Utilization of Applied Social Research, 1949 (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Finance Attitude Study, 1948 (Box 207, Folder 6)
  - Handbook on the Drafting of Sociological Studies, 1946-1971, (3 Folders) (Box 352, Folder 7-9)
  - Harvard Business School Study, 1961-1962 (Box 352, Folder 10)
  - Hours Spent on Community Activity in Decatur, undated (Box 207, Folder 7)
  - Housing Study
    - General, 1945-1954 (Box 207, Folder 8)
    - General, undated (Box 352, Folder 11)
    - Addison Terrace
      - Card Design, 1953, undated (Box 207, Folder 9)
      - Code Book, 1947, (2 Folders) (Box 207, Folder 10-11)
    - "The Analysis of Community Researchers," 1947 (Box 207, Folder 12)
    - Charts, undated (Box 207, Folder 13)
    - Citizens' Housing Council of New York, Inc., 1946-1950 (Box 207, Folder 14)
    - Commission on Race and Housing, 1956-1957 (Box 207, Folder 15)
    - Community Ethos, undated, 1950, (2 Folders) (Box 207, Folder 16-17)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1947 (Box 207, Folder 18)
      - Wurster, Catherine Bauer, 1948-1951 (Box 207, Folder 19)
    - Craftown
      - and Hilltown--Detailed Descriptions, circa 1947 (Box 207, Folder 20)
      - and Winfield--Memoranda and Drafts, 1945-1946, (5 Folders) (Box 208, Folder 1-5)
    - File Index, undated (Box 208, Folder 6)
    - Friendship
      - General, circa 1950s, (3 Folders) (Box 208, Folder 7-9)
      - Background Research, undated (Box 208, Folder 10)
      - Card Design, undated (Box 208, Folder 11)
      - Cross Currents, 1952-1966 (Box 209, Folder 1)
      - Drafts, 1945 (Box 209, Folder 2)
      - Memoranda, 1944-1952 (Box 209, Folder 3)
      - Tables and Notes, 1952-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 209, Folder 4-5)
    - Interim Report, 1946 (Box 209, Folder 6)
    - Isolates Tables, undated (Box 209, Folder 7)
    - Lavanburg Foundation
      - Budget, 1945-1947 (Box 209, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1944-1961, (2 Folders) (Box 209, Folder 9-10)
      - Report, 1949 (Box 210, Folder 1)
    - Notes
      - General, circa 1945, (2 Folders) (Box 210, Folder 2-3)
      - Race Relations, 1949 (Box 210, Folder 4)
    - Patterns of Social Life: Explorations in the Sociology of Housing (with Patricia S. West and Marie Jahoda)
      - Annotated Typescript, 1948, (5 Folders) (Box 210, Folder 5-9)
      - Annotated Typescript, 1948, (9 Folders) (Box 211, Folder 1-9)
      - Annotated Typescript, 1948, (2 Folders) (Box 212, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence and Edits, 1968-1987 (Box 352, Folder 12)
      - Drafts
        - General, 1946-1949, undated, (8 Folders) (Box 212, Folder 3-10)
        - General, 1946-1949, undated, (10 Folders) (Box 213, Folder 1-10)
        - General, 1946-1949, undated, (7 Folders) (Box 214, Folder 1-7)
        - and Memoranda, undated (Box 214, Folder 8)
        - and Memoranda, undated (Box 215, Folder 1)
        - Table of Contents, undated (Box 215, Folder 2)
      - Reference Material, 1939-1943 (Box 215, Folder 3)
      - Requests for Copies, 1961-1978 (Box 215, Folder 4)
    - "Selected Problems of Field Work in the Planned Community," 1946 (Box 215, Folder 5)
    - "Social Fictions and Social Facts: The Dynamics of Race Relations in Hilltown," 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 215, Folder 6-7)
    - "The Social Psychology of Housing," 1948 (Box 215, Folder 8)
    - Training Guide, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 215, Folder 9-11)
    - Training Guide, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 216, Folder 1-2)
    - Winfield
      - General, 1945 (Box 216, Folder 3)
      - Card Design, undated (Box 216, Folder 4)
      - Code Book, 1945-1946, (5 Folders) (Box 216, Folder 5-9)
      - Questionnaires, 1945-1946 (Box 216, Folder 10)
  - Human Relations Area Files, Inc.--Cross Cultural Survey, 1948-1953 (Box 216, Folder 11)
  - Kikuchi Diary Study, 1947-1950 (Box 217, Folder 1)
  - LIFE Magazine Ubiquity Study, 1947-1948 (Box 217, Folder 2)
  - Manhattanville Project
    - General, 1946-1950, (3 Folders) (Box 217, Folder 3-5)
    - Audio Recording--Hogrefe, 1949 (Audograph Electronic Disc) (Box 237, Folder 1)
    - Data Analysis by Students, 1950 (Box 217, Folder 6)
    - Interviews and Field Observations
      - Sections 1, 2, and 4, 1949-1950 (3 Bound Volumes) (Box 218)
      - Section 3, 1949-1950 (Bound Volume) (Box 219)
    - Participant Observation, 1950, (2 Folders) (Box 217, Folder 7-8)
  - National Opinion Research Center--Correspondence and Agreements, 1948-1952 (Box 220, Folder 1)
  - New Orleans Elite--Preliminary Data, 1940 (Box 220, Folder 2)
  - New York Television Study, 1952-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 220, Folder 3-4)
  - New York Time Budget Study, 1945-1946, (2 Folders) (Box 220, Folder 5-6)
  - New York Time Budget Study, 1944 (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - Office of Radio Research--Time Magazine Readership and the Influence Structure of Dover New Jersey
    - Notes, Drafts and Correspondence, 1943-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 220, Folder 7-8)
    - Reports, 1943, (2 Folders) (Box 220, Folder 9-10)
  - Proposed
    - Comparative Study of Social Mobility, Its Causes and Consequences, 1954 (Box 220, Folder 11)
    - Judicial Personnel, 1947 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Negro Medical Students, 1969 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - Public Reaction to Sonic Booms--Air Force Office of Scientific Research, 1965 (Box 221, Folder 3)
    - Sociology of Complex Organizations, 1958 (Box 221, Folder 4)
  - Radio Program Content Analysis, 1943 (Box 221, Folder 5)
  - Sociological Study of Medical Education
    - General, 1951-1961, (4 Folders) (Box 221, Folder 6-9)
    - Analysis of Material for Concept Formation, 1951-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 221, Folder 10-11)
    - Association of American Medical Colleges Conference, 1957-1958 (Box 222, Folder 1)
    - Background Material on Schools, 1952-1959 (Box 222, Folder 2)
    - Code Books
      - General, undated, 1956-1961, (5 Folders) (Box 222, Folder 3-7)
      - Cornell University Medical College, 1952-1956, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 222, Folder 8-11)
      - Cornell University Medical College, 1952-1956, undated (10 Folders (Box 223, Folder 1-10)
      - Corrections, 1952-1957 (Box 224, Folder 1)
      - Inventory, 1954-1955 (Box 224, Folder 2)
      - University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, 1953-1955, (8 Folders) (Box 224, Folder 3-10)
      - Western Reserve University School of Medicine, 1953-1954, (6 Folders) (Box 225, Folder 1-6)
    - Committee on Medical Sociology, 1955 (Box 225, Folder 7)
    - Comparative Study of the Internship and Residency
      - Budget and Finance, 1952-1961 (Box 225, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 225, Folder 10)
      - "The Internship: An Exploratory Analysis by Theresa Falaguerra," 1957 (Box 225, Folder 11)
      - Proposal, 1958, (3 Folders) (Box 226, Folder 1-3)
      - Seminar Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 226, Folder 4)
    - Concept of Socialization, undated (Box 225, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1955 (Box 226, Folder 5)
      - American Medical Association, 1958 (Box 226, Folder 6)